Are desiccated thyroid hormones going
away? On August 6th, 2025, yes, just a
few days ago, the FDA issued a letter to
manufacturers, importers, and
distributors of these desecated thyroid
hormones that they will now need to
pursue a biologics license in order to
continue offering these products. In the
letter, the FDA also referred to these
desecated thyroid products as ADTS or
animal derived thyroid products. If you
aren't aware, it would affect drugs such
as nature thyroid, NP thyroid, armor
thyroid, nathyroid, as well as adisa or
even compound versions of those. As of
right now, it's speculated that there's
somewhere in the ballpark of about 1 and
a half to 2 million people who currently
use these NDT products. Here's the big
problem with this is that obtaining a
biologics license is incredibly
expensive, very cumbersome, and it is a
lengthy process. Remember about five or
six years ago when HCG became
reclassified as a biologic and then
numerous compoundies went from offering
it to practically overnight pulling the
plug on it. Now HCG is incredibly hard
to obtain from a compounding pharmacy.
You for most people they have to go the
name brand route. Well, this could also
happen to these thyroid medications and
that would increase the difficulty of
accessibility to these medications. As
of right now, it does not appear the FDA
is taking action against any of these
manufacturers or distributors. But per
the letter, it does appear that there's
about a one-year grace period so that
patients can get converted transitioned
over to the other traditional products
such as levothyoxine or liioyronine. If
you want to learn more about this, I
have the web address posted right up
here.